Finding Aid for the Program for Art on Film Records, 1951-1999, undated IA20008
Institutional Records and Archives
- Records collected by the Program for Art on Film, 1951-1998; undated; (bulk 1984-1994); Series II.; 51.8 Linear Feet; (45 boxes, 3 framed posters, 2 flat files)
  - Subject Files, 1973-1998; Series II.E.; 10 Linear Feet; (12 boxes)
    - Subject files:
      - Vienna and the Cinema, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-56A)
      - V.I.E.W. Video, 1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-59A)
      - Viewfinders, Inc., 1994-1995 (Box 2004.IA.14-59A)
      - Vineyard Video Productions, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-59A)
      - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts: TEAMS, 1993-1996 (Box 2004.IA.14-59A)
      - The Voyager Company, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.14-59A)
      - V.P.I./A.C. Video, Inc., 1993-1994 (Box 2004.IA.14-59A)
      - W, 1983-1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-59A)
      - Warhol, 1988; 1990,; 1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-56A)
      - West Glen Films, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-59A)
      - Weston Woods, 1987-1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-59A)
      - WETA, 1986-1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-59A)
      - Clem Williams Films, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-59A)
      - Women's Films, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.14-56A)
      - Words in Art, 1989; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-23)
      - Wyeth, Andrew, [empty folder], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-56A)
      - X [empty folder], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-59A)
      - Y, 1987-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-59A)
      - Yugoslav Films, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-56A)
      - Z, 1990-1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-59A)
    - Film reviews (clippings):
      - Reviews to File, 1994-1996 (Box 2004.IA.14-13)
      - A, 1982-1995; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-13)
      - B, 1984-1995; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-13)
      - C, 1985-1994; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-13)
      - D, 1982-1994; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-13)
      - E, 1987-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-13)
      - F, 1980-1994; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-13)
      - G, 1984-1994; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-13)
      - H, 1985-1994; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-13)
      - I, 1983-1994; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-13)
      - J, 1985-1992; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-13)
      - K, 1988-1994; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-13)
      - L, 1987-1996; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-13)
      - M, 1985-1993; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-13)
      - N, 1987-1998; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-13)
      - O, 1982-1994; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-13)
      - P, 1981-1994; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-13)
  - "People Files", 1960-1996; Series II.F.; 3.2 Linear Feet; (5 boxes)
    Records consist of correspondence, resumes, clippings, and printed matter describing artists (both contemporary and deceased, working in a variety of media), filmmakers, art historians, and other individuals with interest in film and/or the arts, collected by the Program for Art on Film, 1960-1996. Some of the individuals represented in the records served as evaluators for the Program's publications (including its films). The bulk of the information was used to compile the Art on Screen ("Critical Inventory") database.
    - Abramowicz, Miriam, 1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Perry Miller Adato, 1986-1995; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Amarger, Michael, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Andersen, Stig, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Erica Anderson, 1983-1984 (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Ralph Arlyck, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Aronow, Vera, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Miriam Arsham, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Artists, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Art Historians and Educators A-G, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Art Historians and Educators H-Z, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Franklin Backus and Richard Protovin, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Baldessari, John, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Jacques Barsac, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Bass, Saul, 1995-1996; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Baumbruck, Michael, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Bauman, Suzanne, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Beirne, Bill, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Bennet, Merilee, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Berg, Chuck (film historian), 1990-1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Bernier, Rosamond, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Beuys, Joseph, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Bianchi, Lois, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Blank, Les, 1987; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Blumberg, Skip, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Blumenthal, Lyn, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Bouchard, Thomas, 1984 (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Boxer, Eileen, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Brunie, Patrick, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Bourne, St. Clair, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Aram Boyajian, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Brandon, Liane, 1987-1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Eric Breitbart, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Bank, Mirra Brockman, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Broodthaers, Marcel, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Bruno, Taddeo, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Molly Burgess, 1983-1984; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Ken Burns, 1985; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Camerini, Michael, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Cashin, Bonnie, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Chase, Doris, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Christo, 1977-1978 (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Tim Chu, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - DP Curtis Clark, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Clarke, Martha, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Conklin, Gary, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Conner, Bruce, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Connor, Russell, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Cox, Paul, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Csaky, Mick, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Damisch, Teri Wehn, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Danska, Herb, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Danto, Arthur, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Davis, Carl, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Davis, Curtis, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - DeCostere, Stefaan, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Demetrios, Eames, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - DeNonno, Tony, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - De Olazabal, Eugenia, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Descamps, Olivier, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Dhelsing, Marie-Dominique, 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Dibb, Michael, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Downey, Juan, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Carl Th. Dreyer, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Jean Marie Drot, 1981; 1984 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Drupsteen, Jaap, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Ron Du Bois, 1983; 1985-1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Duget, Anne Marie, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Luciano Emmer, 1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Michele Emmer, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Erice, Victory [Victor], 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Evaluation Panelists: resumes, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Buzz Evers, 1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Falkenberg/Namuth, 1985 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Filmmakers Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Finster, Howard, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Flaherty, Robert, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Judi Fogelman: Films About Animation, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Warren Forma, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Foery, Raymond, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Frank, Robert, 1994 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Freed, Hermine, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Friedl, Erik, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Fulchignoni, Enrico, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Renee Furst, 1985 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Galentine, Wheaton, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Gerson, Barry, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Gill, Brendan, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Glintenkamp, Pamela, 1991; 1995 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Gold, Mick, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Gombrich, Sir Ernst, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Graves, Nancy, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Prod. file: Greaves, William, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Greenway [Greenaway], Peter, 1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Griffiths, Keith/Brothers Quay, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Grigor, Murray, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - George Griffin, 1975; 1982,; 1985 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Grubin, David, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Guggenheim, Charles, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Philip Haas, 1990-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Halpern, John, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Henson, Jim, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Herbert, James, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Lynn Hershman, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Hillman and Carr, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Hockney, David, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Horn, Rebecca, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Hoving, Thomas, 1992-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Hubley, Emily, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Hurtado, Angel, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Iimura, Taka, 1992-1993; 1995 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Inocencio, David, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Ironside, David, 1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Isozaki, Arata, 1988; 1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Al Jarnow, 1983 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Jacobs, Ellen, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Johnston, Steve, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Jones, Jeffrey Owen, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Ivens, Joris, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Jost, Jon, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Kaplan, Nelly, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Etien Kapon, 1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Keefer, Cindy, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Kirkeby, Per, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - William Klein, 1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Klonarides, Carole Ann, 1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Kogan, Sheila L., undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Kos, Paul, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Kosersky, Rena C., undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Kovacs, Yves, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Krainin, Julian, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Kustow, Michael, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Lamarre, Paul, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Lance, Mary, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Lavine, Steve, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Lehner, Fritz, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Erwin Leiser, 1980; 1996 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Tom Levin (Getty / Princeton / Art/Film Scholar), 1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Levine, Jack, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Les Levine, 1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Lily Ann Productions, Inc., 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Robert Longo, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Lowder, Rose, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Lucier, Mary, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Lyman, Charles, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Mallory-Jones, Philip, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Babette Mangolte, 1985 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Matsumoto, Toshio, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Maysles Bros., 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Maze, Fabrice, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - McElfresh, Sam, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - McLaren, Norman, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - McLaren, Norman, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - McMullen, Ken, 1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Leslei Megahey, 1985 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Mekas, Jonas, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Merchant, Ismail, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Merchant Ivory, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Miles, William, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Mili, Gjon, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Minh-ha, Trin, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Monk, Meredith, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Monk, Meredith, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Monster, Ruud, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Montgomery, Steven, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Monticello, Roberto, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Mora, Juan, 1982; 1984,; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Moreau, Jeanne, 1973 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Morgan, Anne, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Moritz, Reiner, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Morris, Susan, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Morrison, Rita Rosenthal, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Mouris, Frank and Caroline, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Murphy, Susan, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Musser, Charles, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Namuth, Hans, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Nole, Leonardo, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - O'Doherty, Brian, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Oleari, Claudio, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Olmi, Ermanno, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Paradjanor, Sergei, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Gordon Parks, 1983; 1984 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Pasternak, Gloria, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Patterson, Kathi, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Pearlman, Judith, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - D.A. Pennebaker, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Petrie, Daniel, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Mildred Pollner, 1985 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Polomski, Stephen, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - [Production Files], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Producer file/ Composers/Musicians, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Producers (eval. panelists, etc.), undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Programmers' (eval. panelists, etc.), undated (Box 2004.IA.14-8A)
    - Quay, Timothy and Stephen (The Brothers Quay), 1987; 1989,; 1991,; 1996 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Rappaport, Mark, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Hary Rasky, 1992; 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - John Read, 1960; 1970,; 1983,; 1984 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Rhodes, Lucille, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - RIFF, 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Rigolini, Luciano, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Ripeau, Marie-Genevieve, 1985 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Rivlin, Lilly, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Robbe-Grillet, Alain, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Rogers, Richard, 1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Stephanie Rose/Randall Schmit, 1989-1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Peter Rose, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Rosen, Bob, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Ruiz, Raul, 1987-1988; 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Rybczynski, Zbignew, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Sadan, Mark, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Ben Sarao, 1984 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Sargent, Naomi, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Schamoni, Peter, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Schapiro, Meyer, 1987; 1994 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Schwartz, Lillian, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Schwarz, Tony, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Schwerfel, Heinz Peter, 1988; 1992,; 1994 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Gene Searchinger, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Searchinger, Gene, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Helen Jean Secondari, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Sedelmaier, Joe, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - See, Jean Claude, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Harvard and Waltraud Seebock, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Segal, Abraham, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Segal, Abraham, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Shedd, Ben, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Sher, Elizabeth, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Slesin, Aviva, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Smith, Bo, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Snow, Michael, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - R. Snyder, 1982 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Robert D. Squier, 1985 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Cecile Starr, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Steiner, Ralph, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Stanojevic, Stanislav, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Storck, Henri, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Strand, Paul, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Tanner, Alain, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Catherine Tatge, 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Katherine Duetch Tatlock, 1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Teitzell, Jay, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Anita Thacher, 1985; 1987,; undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Thomas, Karen, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Thompson, David, 1983 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Thompson, Marylee, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Timreck, T.W., 1985 (Box 2004.IA.14-40)
    - Tomczak, Gregor, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Tougas, Kirk, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Traubner, Andrea, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Trumbull, 1985 (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Ungerer, Walter, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Unity Productions, 1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - [Untitled], 1989; 1990,; 1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-49)
    - Georgia van der Rohe, 1982 (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Van Dulmen, Alexander, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Van Dyke, Barbara, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Van Dyke, Willard, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Varda, Agnes, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Varnedoe, Kirk, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Vaughn, Jeff, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Vecchiet, Jean-Michel, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Velez, Eden, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Villardebo, Carlos, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Bill Viola, 1983; 1987,; 1995 (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Amos Vogel, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Von Praunheim: Producer, 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Wada, Emi, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Andy Warhol, 1988; 1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Washizu, Toshi, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Judith Wechsler, 1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Wegman, William, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Leigh Weiner, 1985 (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Werner, Tom, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Whitney, Betsey, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Whitney, Helen, 1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Wyler, Catherine, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - John Wyver Illuminations, 1983-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Yentob, Alan, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Zanoli, Anna, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-22)
    - Zeno, Thierry, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
    - Charlotte Zwerin, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-68)
  - Film Festival Files, 1959-1997; Series II.G.; 8.7 Linear Feet; (1 flat file equivalent)
    These records are listed primarily in the order found within the original accession; some of the entries have been alphabetized for ease of reading.
    Records consist of printed matter, press releases, clippings, correspondence, and posters collected by the Program for Art on Film, 1959-1998, that document film festivals. These festivals, both national and international, were concerned specifically with films about art.
    Much of the material exists in duplicate form.
    - Film festival information:
      - AFI Fest, 1986-1989; 1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-54A)
      - American Film and Video Festival, 1984-1989; 1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-54A)
      - American Film Festival Guide, 1981; 1983,; 1985-1986,; 1990-1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-54A)
      - American Film Festival, 1984-1987; (4 folders) (Box 2004.IA.14-41)
      - Amsterdam: Arts for TV Symposium, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-54A)
      - Antwerp: Films on Art, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-54A)
      - ASOLO, 1982; 1991,; 1994 (Box 2004.IA.14-54A)
      - Athens International Film/Video Festivals, 1984-1985; 1997 (Box 2004.IA.14-54A)
      - Aubusson: International Arts and Crafts Films Festival, 1983-1984 (Box 2004.IA.14-54A)
      - Banff Int'l TV Festival, 1983-1984; 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-54A)
      - Barcelona: cinemadart '87, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-54A)
      - Bilbao (Documentary and Short Film), 1981-1985 (Box 2004.IA.14-54A)
      - Brussels...Art History and Archaeology Festival, 1983; 1986-1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-54A)
      - Cinemadart, 1987; 1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-54A)
      - Ecran d'Art, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-54A)
      - European Biennial of the Documentary, 1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-54A)
      - European Télé-Musée Conference, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-54A)
      - FIFARC, 1984; 1987,; 1990,; 1992-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-54A)
      - International du Film d'Archeologie et d'Ethnologie (Aud. du Louvre), 1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-54B)
      - International du Film d'Archeologie de Paris, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-54B)
      - Jewish Film Festival, 1984 (Box 2004.IA.14-54B)
      - KNOKKE International Festival of Films on Art, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-54B)
      - Lausanne: Fest. Int'l du Film d'Architecture/d'Urbanism, 1987; 1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-54B)
      - Naples: Arte and Cinema, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.14-54B)
      - Nyon, 1981-1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-54B)
      - Padua: Exhib. of Films on Art, 1985-1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-54B)
      - Paris: Centre Pompidou Festival du Film sur l'Art, 1990; 1996 (Box 2004.IA.14-54B)
      - Paris: Festival du film du Patrimoine, 1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-54B)
      - Paris: Festival Int'l du Film d'Art, 1981; 1985-1987,; 1989-1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-54B)
      - Rotterdamn-Films on Art Festival, 1986; 1988,; 1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-54B)
      - Slovakia: Art Film Festival, 1993-1995 (Box 2004.IA.14-54B)
    - Posters (Box 2004.IA.14-131)
      [American Independent Film Festival, Berlin 1990; Projections: Bibliotheque National du Quebec, International Festival of Films on Art, 1981; Hollywood: Legend and Reality; Films Over Kunst; Le Musée d'Art Contemporain de Montreal, 2e Festival International du Film sur l'Art, 1982.]
    - Posters (Box 2004.IA.14-136)
      [Films on Art 1988; 4e Festival International du Film sur l'Art, 1985; Cites-Cines; 3e Festival International du Film sur l'Art, 1984; Strokes of Genius; Cinemadart '87; 9e Festival International du Film sur l'Art; 8e Festival International du Film sur l'Art, 1990.]
  - Visual material, circa 1980-1999; Series II.H.; 11.4 Linear Feet; (8 boxes, 3 framed posters, 1 flat file)
    These records are listed by type of object.
    Records consist of posters, slides, and image-oriented visual arts software. The posters included in the records are generally advertisements for films; also included are photographic images of two projects by the artist Christo.
    - Posters and slides:
      - [Posters: Spend a Day with a Knight at the Metropolitan Museum of Art; Ansel Adams: Examples; 1a Mostra Internazionale del documentario sull'Arte, 1985], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-132)
      - [Posters: Portrait of Jennie (Jennifer Jones and Joseph Cotten); The Mystery of Picasso], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-133)
      - [Posters: Gauguin: The Wolf at the Door; Hopper's Silence; Picture of Dorian Gray; Dazzle Painting, 1987; Erinnerung], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-134)
      - [Posters: The Naked Maja (Ava Gardner, Anthony Franciosa); Vincent: The Life and Death of Vincent van Gogh], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-135)
      - [Posters: Florentine Films: The Shakers: Hands to Work, Hearts to God; Musée du Louvre; The Happiness of Still Life (2 copies)], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-137)
      - [Poster: Christo, Wrapped Islands], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-127b)
      - [Poster: Christo, Pont Neuf], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-128)
      - [Poster: The Mystery of Picasso], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-129)
      - [Poster: Primary Colors: The Story of Corita], 1990 (Flatfile 2004.IA.14-130)
        [Limited edition print, signed. Unframed.]
      - [Poster: Musée du Louvre], undated (Flatfile 2004.IA.14-130)
        [Unframed.]
      - [Poster: Jos Stelling's Rembrandt, Fecit 1669], undated; [Unframed; 3 copies.] (Flatfile 2004.IA.14-130)
      - Siggraph Art Show slides, 1988; (83 color slides)
    - Visual arts software:
      - Vermeer: an exploration of the artist and his techniques, 1996; (1 CD) (Box 2004.IA.14-43)
      - Smithsonian Institution National Museum of American Art, 1996; (1 CD) (Box 2004.IA.14-43)
      - New York Time Capsule: The Multimedia Yearbook of 1994, 1995; (1 CD) (Box 2004.IA.14-43)
      - A Passion for Art: Renoir, Cézanne, Matisse, and Dr. Barnes, 1995; (1 CD) (Box 2004.IA.14-43)
      - Van Gogh: The Man, His Life, His Works: an interactive journey through the world of Van Gogh, 1995; (1 CD) (Box 2004.IA.14-43)
      - Cinemania '94 Interactive Movie Guide (Microsoft Home), 1993; (1 CD) (Box 2004.IA.14-43)
      - Microsoft Art Gallery: The Collection of the National Gallery, London, 1993; (1 CD) (Box 2004.IA.14-43)
      - Great Artists: An interactive exploration of their work, lives and times, 1994; (1 CD and printed manual) (Box 2004.IA.14-43)
      - Frank Lloyd Wright: Presentation and Conceptual Drawings, 1994; (4 CDs; 1 3.5 inch disk; printed manual) (Box 2004.IA.14-43)
      - With Open Eyes: Images from the Art Institute of Chicago, 1995; (1 CD) (Box 2004.IA.14-43)